Hello and welcome to the updated lesson on using a US Iot with the updated sdhc.
In the previous lessons we'd integrated the ESP a US Iot released version 3.1 and this was the latest
version at the time of the recording, but has since released a newer version and I'm going to keep
the old version as part of the configuration lesson as some people are still using it.
But for those that want to check out an example of publishing and subscribing using the new version
here, then this lesson is for you.
However, before moving on, please be sure that you've already set up your account, created a thing
in US generated certificates and attach the policy.
Basically, everything we did in the configuration lesson.
So go back and watch that if you haven't already.
So let's get started here by going to the project folder and let's change the name of the existing US
Iot folder.
In case you want to keep this version.
So that is version 3.1.
Now let's copy the clone command they provided for us here.
So copy that.
Like so.
And then go to the project folder.
Because we want to clone it to this folder and right click here.
And then go to get Bashir.
And then paste in the clone command.
And just give it a few moments to finish as it may take a little while.
And now we can close get.
And let's just briefly check out what we have here and our cloned ESP a society folder.
Here are the top level structure looks pretty simple with the examples folder and the libraries folder,
and we'll look into the examples shortly and we'll actually implement the mktg example.
And in the libraries folder, we'll need to include these by adjusting our make list file.
So feel free to get familiar with these files and folders here, especially if you're interested in
diving deeper into a society.
All right.
So now let's review into the example that we're going to implement.
Let's go back to the examples folder.
And the example that we want is an example where we can simply publish and subscribe data.
However, you can always explore the other examples once you know how to integrate this example.
So let's go into MQTT, then let's go into TLS mutual authentication.
And first, let's take a look at the read me that's provided here, because there's a few important
notes there.
First, it says we need to find and set the US endpoint hostname and it says Your Iot account has a
unique endpoint hostname to connect to.
To find it open the US Iot console and click the settings button on the bottom left side and using the
K config project build file.
From this example, we can enter the endpoint host name into the example configuration and the sdhc
config.
So also we need to set the client ID and it says here that the client ID is used in the MQTT Protocol
to send messages to and from a society and a Iot requires that each connected device within a single
US account uses a unique client ID, and if we recall from the configuration lesson, this is the name
of our thing in a society.
And in this example, these definitions are compiled into the menu config, which we can adjust via
the sdhc config file.
All right, so let's just grab that information for now, just as a quick refresher of where we can
find it so that we can easily retrieve it later.
So I'll just create a new text file and from our AWS account.
We can go to Iot core.
And then I'll just set my location.
And then we can go into settings.
And let's grab the endpoint hostname.
Copy it like so.
And then I'll just make a note of it here.
Next.
We want the client to ID.
Let's go to all devices.
Didn't go to things.
And I'll just copy mine.
And then make a note of it here and now.
Let's start integrating the framework and we'll start off by adjusting the top level CMYK list file
and we can actually use the C make list file provided by the example for reference.
So let's just open the make list file provided.
And then let's copy the entire set command right here.
Now go to the top level C make list file in the project.
And we can actually move the set command to the recommended location so we can get rid of this one.
And then pace the command to.
But let's adjust the path here so that it aligns with our folder structure.
We can select this part here.
Then use control f.
And then we could replace it with the correct path to the ESP a US Iot folder here.
All right, so just enter ESP.
A Iot.
Then replace all.
Och.
And that all looks good.
Except we forgot to do one thing and that's to refresh the project as I noticed that a USB Iot version
3.1 folder is missing here.
So what we could do is go to the top level project folder and right click and then go down to refresh
and refresh the project.
Now we have the old version in the new version right here.
Next, let's copy the necessary files over to the ID by going into the main folder of the example.
So let's head over to the example folder.
Go into the main folder.
And we already have our own app main.
So let's just take the demo config header file.
The config project build file and the MK PT demo source file.
Copy those over.
Choose overwrite for the k config project build file.
Okay, Next we can update the main CMYK list file by copying the name of our new source file.
Go over to the new source file.
And right click on it.
To copy.
Then let's open up the main make list file.
And we can override the old a society source file.
With the new file name here.
And just be sure to save that.
Next, let's update our main see.
And let's use the app and see from the example it's a reference.
Go ahead and open that file.
And the only thing that we need here is the entry point to the demo application, and that is this function
here.
So copy the prototype and let's go back and paste it in.
Okay.
Now just adjust it like so.
Let's also grab the function call.
And the function call is here.
Just copy that and let's go back and paste it into our wi fi application.
Connected events callback function.
And that's because we'll need an Internet connection prior to connecting to a society.
We can also comment out the old US Iot start function call.
Comment this out and we can also get rid of the include for the old a US Iot header.
And that's all we'll need to do here.
Next, let's briefly review the code provided by the example and make some changes wherever necessary.
Let's start with a demo config header file.
And let's just go through this briefly.
The endpoint here will come from the sdhc config once we update it.
And the MQTT port will come from the configuration as well.
And the client identifier also comes from the sdhc config and that will be updated with our thing.
Name.
And the network buffer size also comes from the sdhc config as well as the hardware platform name.
And we'll see how these definitions are defined when we update the sdhc config shortly.
So now let's take a look at the MQTT demo mutual authentication C file.
And this file contains everything that we need to run the demo.
But of course we need to update it so that we can publish the temperature, humidity and the wi fi RSI
and so that it works with our AWS Iot accounts.
So first let's add the include for the PH 22 sensor, and that is so that we can publish the temperature
and humidity.
And let's include the wi fi app as well and that so that we can publish the wi fi RSI.
So also at the top of the file, we have to adjust the root CA definition, the client certificate and
the private key as well.
So let's go ahead and copy the US root CA file name and we can get that from our certs folder.
And then right click.
Then copy.
And let's paste it in for the root CA binary data start.
And for the binary data end as well.
Now we can do the same for the client certificate.
So let's go back to the search folder and then I will just control see.
And then we could paste it in for the start.
Let's do the end as well.
Now for the private key.
Control C to copy and paste it in for the start.
And the end.
Now let's continue down the file.
We have some more defines here for the endpoint link and also the client identifier length and so on.
And then there's also connection re tris and then some others that you may want to look into for customizing
this example.
And here's an important one, which we'll have to update.
This is our topic name, which we had used in the previous a Iot example for publishing of subscribing
to and previously we had defined it in the US Iot C file.
So let's head over there.
And I will just control left to search for it.
And this is how I define mine.
All right.
So I'll go ahead and copy this.
And then go back to the new example file.
And then update the definition here.
And again, this is the topic to subscribe and publish to.
And let's keep moving this example message here we actually won't use as we're going to publish the
temperature humidity and we fire our Cici.
And as we can see from the outline here.
There are quite a few definitions and function prototypes, and I suggest that you go through these
on your own.
If you're interested in customizing this example and adapting it to suit your application needs.
Because what's important for us right now is publishing data to this topic.
We don't want to publish this Hello world message, so let's find out where this definition is used
by using control f.
And here we find that it's used within the published atomic function where the payload and the payload
length are updated with these macro definitions.
So instead of sending the Hello world, let's give it the temperature, humidity and wi fi r a C and
give it the new payload length as well.
And in order to do that, we can grab our print def statement from the old example.
So let's head back over to society.
And we could find that in the a society task.
And let's just copy this line here.
And let's just paste it towards the top of the function.
And we also want the wi fi outside.
So let's add in the text for that.
And then let's give it the function that is wi fi app.
Get RC.
And then why fi RSI is a string.
And the result from the function is an integer.
And let's define the C payload variable up here as well.
All right.
And then we want to update the payload with our C payload variable.
Which will now contain the RSI, temperature and humidity.
And then we also want to provide the length of the payload and we can use str len for that.
And that's all we need to do.
And again, if you want to dig deeper, I suggest reviewing this source file in more detail.
But for now, let's take a look at the US Iot demo main function and check out the description for a
quick overview.
And here it says that the example shown below uses MQTT APIs to send and receive MQTT packets over the
TLS connection established using OpenSSL.
The example is single threaded and uses statically allocated memory.
It uses quality of service level one and therefore implements a retransmission mechanism for published
messages.
So that covers the basics.
And now let's move on to build the project so that we can generate the SDK config file and update the
necessary variables.
So let's go ahead and build the project.
So now let's continue to the sdhc config.
And then here in the example configuration, we can update the client identifier and the endpoint of
the MQTT broker to connect to.
So let's copy the endpoint.
And just paste it in.
But now let's grab the client identify identifier.
And paste it in here.
And be sure to save the configuration.
All right.
So now we can go ahead and flesh it.
Once we're flesh, we'll open the monitor and then head over to the US Iot MQTT Test client.
So let's go ahead and flesh.
So that's okay.
I can just hit.
Proceed.
And I actually forgot to choose my port.
So I'll go ahead and do that.
And then I'll flash again.
Okay, then.
Now we can open the monitor.
Now I'm connecting with the save credentials.
And I'm already showing the published data.
Great.
So next, we can head over to a society and we can check out the activity from that end.
So let's head over there.
And let's click on our thing.
Let's go to the activity tab.
And then here we see the subscribed and connected events.
So that's what our subscribed event looks like.
And the connected.
So now let's go to the MQTT test client.
And then select the topic.
And there we have our published data, the wi fi, RSI, the temperature and the humidity being published
at the interval provided by the example that looks great.
So next, if you want to test publishing from the MQTT test client, we can set the monitors side by
side with a society and then view the activity from the monitor side.
So let's go ahead and put these side by side.
And then.
Now let's hit publish.
And there we go.
The messages are being received on the ESP 332 from a W society.
And that is very cool.
So now that you know how to integrate an example from this version of the ESP a AWS Iot SDK, then you
should have a solid foundation for exploring further on your own.
All right.
So thanks for joining me this far into the course and I hope to see you again soon.